Guide to the Seattle Opportunities Industrialization Center Records
Special Collections, University of Washington Libraries
Opportunities Industrialization Center records
1966-1988
University of Washington Libraries Special Collections Box 352900 Seattle, WA 98195-2900
4055
4055-001
Seattle Opportunities Industrialization Center
12.54 cubic feet (11 boxes)
Records of the Seattle-based community vocational center that provided pre-apprenticeship training from 1966 to 1986.
OIC Seattle (often refered to locally as "SOIC") was incorporated in May 1966 as a private, nonprofit community-based vocational training center. It was founded as an outgrowth of the OIC movement which had been started two years earlier in Philadelphia. In 1972, OIC Seattle became the first community-based organization to receive federal designation as a Skills Center. Its rapid growth and expanding programs made possible the building of a multi-million dollar training center dedicated in 1974. OIC Seattle's diversified funding and its accreditation saved the school from the financial collapse experienced at the beginning of the 1980s by many similar institutions, but it could not survive the federal government's rapid and drastic cutback of funding around 1983 and 1984. It attempted to continue its services by totally reorganizing its service delivery system. Efforts continued another two years but on September 25, 1986, a Chapter 11 bankruptcy notice was filed.
The collection is arranged into the following series and subseries:
SERIES 1: HISTORICAL/ORGANIZATIONAL FEATURES, 1966-1986
SERIES 2: NEWSLETTERS AND BROCHURES, 1970-1986
SERIES 3: MINUTES, 1966-1988
SERIES 4: FINANCIAL RECORDS, 1972-1986
SERIES 5: REPORTS, 1968-1986
SERIES 6: CONTRACTS, 1968-1983
SERIES 7: PUBLICITY AND PUBLIC RELATIONS RECORDS, 1967-1985
Subseries 1: Speeches, Advertising and Publications 1967-1985
Subseries 2: Photographs 1967-1985
SERIES 8: PLANNING AND FACILITY RECORDS, 1971-1987
SERIES 9: PUBLICATIONS, 1974-1983
Board minutes, 1968-1988; historical documents; publications; financial records; reports; contracts; planning and facility development records; public relations and publicity records; video and film materials; and a large number of photographs illustrating SOIC activities, most of which are 8 x 10" black-and-white prints with related 35mm negatives and contact sheets.
The Workforce Training & Education Coordinating Board maintains records (transcripts) for closed schools in Washington State, including the Seattle Opportunities Industrialization Center. For more information about accessing these transcripts, see their Closed School Transcript Request webpage.
Forms part of the Labor Archives of Washington.
Open to all users.
Records are stored offsite; advance notice is required for use.
Donated by Opportunities Industrialization Center, Seattle, 10/31/1989.
Vocational training centers$zWashington (State)$zSeattle; Minutes (Records); Photographs; Newsletters; Contracts; Financial records; McKinney, Samuel B.$vArchives; Isaki, Paul; Williams, James L.; Charles, John; Seattle Opportunities Industrialization Center$vArchives; Labor Archives of Washington (University of Washington); Vocation training centers$zWashington (State)$zSeattle$vArchives; Personal Papers/Corporate Records; Civic Activism; Washington (State); Seattle
- HISTORICAL/ORGANIZATIONAL FEATURES, 1966-1986; SERIES 1 (Box-folder 1/1 - 1/13)
  - Background & history, 1980-1982 (Box-folder 1/1)
  - Proposal to Seattle Public Schools, 1986 (Box-folder 1/2)
  - By-Laws and Articles of Incorporation, 1966 (Box-folder 1/3)
  - Final historical summary, 1986 (Box-folder 1/4)
  - By-Laws and Articles of Incorporation, 1973 (Box-folder 1/5)
  - History and Comprehensive Service of Seattle Opportunities Industrialization Center, 1985 (Box-folder 1/6)
  - Sponsorship proposal to NACO from King-Snohomish Manpower Consortium, 1979 (Box-folder 1/7)
  - Dedication of Skills Booklet, 1974 (Box-folder 1/8)
  - U.S. Department of Justice INS Petition Approval, 1981 (Box-folder 1/9)
  - Restructure of Counseling Services, 1984 (Box-folder 1/10)
  - Comprehensive Employment and Training Act Review, 1977-1983 (Box-folder 1/11)
  - The Essence of OIC, undated (Box-folder 1/12)
  - Photographs, undated (Box-folder 1/13)
- NEWSLETTERS AND BROCHURES, 1970-1986; SERIES 2 (Box-folder 1/14 - 1/29)
  - Newsletters: Internal Forum, Insight, The Voice, 1970-1984 (Box-folder 1/14)
  - Funding requests brochures, undated (Box-folder 1/15)
  - Job training brochures, undated (Box-folder 1/16)
  - Progress Report brochures, 1978-1981 (Box-folder 1/17)
  - Course catalogs and brochures, 1981-1986 (Box-folder 1/18)
  - Biennial Report, 1973-1979 (Box-folder 1/19)
  - Business and Private Programs brochure, 1974 (Box-folder 1/20)
  - A Guide for Citizens in Pierce, King & Snohomish Counties, c. 1978 (Box-folder 1/21)
  - Opportunities Industrialization Centers of America. Career Intern Program, 1977 (Box-folder 1/22)
  - "OH I SEE!" leaflets describing training programs, undated (Box-folder 1/23)
  - A Strategic Model for Seattle Opportunities Industrialization Center, 1981 (Box-folder 1/24)
  - Partnerships with business and industry, 1971-1975 (Box-folder 1/25)
  - OIC Building for the Future, 1975 (Box-folder 1/26)
  - Asian Counseling and Referral Service. Asian Youth Resource Manual, 1979 (Box-folder 1/27)
  - James R. McGraw. Training as a Mission.- reprint from Adherent], undated (Box-folder 1/28)
  - [OICs of America Region IX Conference Program, 1979 (Box-folder 1/29)
- MINUTES, 1966-1988; SERIES 3 (Box-folder 1/30 - 3/9)
  - Board of Directors minutes, 1966-1969 (Box-folder 1/30)
  - Board of Directors minutes, 1970 (Box-folder 1/31)
  - Board of Directors minutes (part 1 of 4), 1971 (Box-folder 1/32)
  - Board of Directors minutes (part 2 of 4), 1971 (Box-folder 1/33)
  - Board of Directors minutes (part 3 of 4), 1971 (Box-folder 1/34)
  - Board of Directors minutes (part 4 of 4), 1971 (Box-folder 1/35)
  - Board of Directors minutes (part 1 of 3), 1973 (Box-folder 1/36)
  - Board of Directors minutes (part 2 of 3), 1973 (Box-folder 1/37)
  - Board of Directors minutes (part 3 of 3), 1973 (Box-folder 1/38)
  - Board of Directors minutes (part 1 of 5), 1974 (Box-folder 1/39)
  - Board of Directors minutes (part 2 of 5), 1974 (Box-folder 2/1)
  - Board of Directors minutes (part 3 of 5), 1974 (Box-folder 2/2)
  - Board of Directors minutes (part 4 of 5), 1974 (Box-folder 2/3)
  - Board of Directors minutes (part 5 of 5), 1974 (Box-folder 2/4)
  - Board of Directors minutes (part 1 of 2), 1975 (Box-folder 2/5)
  - Board of Directors minutes (part 2 of 2), 1975 (Box-folder 2/6)
  - Board of Directors minutes (part 1 of 2), 1976 (Box-folder 2/7)
  - Board of Directors minutes (part 2 of 2), 1976 (Box-folder 2/8)
  - Board of Directors minutes (part 1 of 2), 1977 (Box-folder 2/9)
  - Board of Directors minutes (part 2 of 2), 1977 (Box-folder 2/10)
  - Board of Directors minutes (part 1 of 2), 1978 (Box-folder 2/11)
  - Board of Directors minutes (part 2 of 2), 1978 (Box-folder 2/12)
  - Board of Directors minutes (part 1 of 2), 1979 (Box-folder 2/13)
  - Board of Directors minutes (part 2 of 2), 1979 (Box-folder 2/14)
  - Board of Directors minutes (part 1 of 3), 1980 (Box-folder 2/15)
  - Board of Directors minutes (part 2 of 3), 1980 (Box-folder 2/16)
  - Board of Directors minutes (part 3 of 3), 1980 (Box-folder 2/17)
  - Board of Directors minutes (part 1 of 2), 1981 (Box-folder 2/18)
  - Board of Directors minutes (part 2 of 2), 1981 (Box-folder 2/19)
  - Board of Directors minutes (part 1 of 2), 1982 (Box-folder 2/20)
  - Board of Directors minutes (part 2 of 2), 1982 (Box-folder 2/21)
  - Board of Directors minutes (part 1 of 2), 1983 (Box-folder 3/1)
  - Board of Directors minutes (part 2 of 2), 1983 (Box-folder 3/2)
  - Board of Directors minutes (part 1 of 2), 1984 (Box-folder 3/3)
  - Board of Directors minutes (part 2 of 2), 1984 (Box-folder 3/4)
  - Board of Directors minutes (part 1 of 2), 1985 (Box-folder 3/5)
  - Board of Directors minutes (part 2 of 2), 1985 (Box-folder 3/6)
  - Board of Directors minutes (part 1 of 2), 1986 (Box-folder 3/7)
  - Board of Directors minutes (part 2 of 2), 1986 (Box-folder 3/8)
  - Board of Directors minutes, 1987-1988 (Box-folder 3/9)
- FINANCIAL RECORDS, 1972-1986; SERIES 4 (Box-folder 3/9 - 3/16)
  - John Charles banking and financial statements, 1986 (Box-folder 3/10)
  - Audit reports, 1972-1974 (Box-folder 3/11)
  - Audit reports, 1975-1976 (Box-folder 3/12)
  - Audit reports, 1976-1981 (Box-folder 3/13)
  - Financial aid programs audit report, 1983 (Box-folder 3/14)
  - Audit reports, 1982-1984 (Box-folder 3/15)
  - Financial report, 1977 (Box-folder 3/16)
- REPORTS, 1968-1986; SERIES 5 (Box-folder 3/17 - 4/17, 6/34 - 6/37)
  - Biennial Reports, 1970-1977 (Box-folder 3/17)
  - Draft biennial reports, 1973-1977 (Box-folder 3/18)
  - Draft biennial reports, 1978-1979 (Box-folder 3/19)
  - Annual report, 1973 (Box-folder 3/20)
  - Draft annual and Thrust Reports, 1975-1976 (Box-folder 3/21)
  - Strategic planning report, 1980 (Box-folder 3/22)
  - Strategic planning report, 1981 (Box-folder 3/23)
  - SOIC OICs of America Annual Report, 1973 (Box-folder 3/24)
  - SOIC Phoenix OIC Annual Report, 1971 (Box-folder 3/25)
  - Reports and brochures, 1979-1981 (Box-folder 3/26)
  - Progress Report, 1968 (Box-folder 4/1)
  - SOIC Final Report, 1968 (Box-folder 4/2)
  - Pre-vocational technical training progress report, 1970 (Box-folder 4/3)
  - Career Intern Program: final report, 1977 (Box-folder 4/4)
  - Program catalog and brochures, 1984-1985 (Box-folder 4/5)
  - Comprehensive Manpower Service Delivery System analysis, 1976 (Box-folder 4/6)
  - Published reports, 1978-1979 (Box-folder 4/7)
  - Self-evaluation report to Accrediting Commission, 1984 (Box-folder 4/8)
  - Report on Corrections Officer Training Program to Accrediting Commission, 1984 (Box-folder 4/9)
  - Self-evaluation report to Council for Non-Collegiate Continuing Education, 1985 (Box-folder 4/10)
  - Self-evaluation report -- revision package -- part 1 of 2, 1985 (Box-folder 4/11)
  - Self-evaluation report -- revision package -- part 2 of 2, 1985 (Box-folder 4/12)
  - Analytic Self-evaluation Report Exhibits -- Part 1 of 4, 1985-1986 (Box-folder 4/13)
  - Analytic Self-evaluation Report Exhibits -- Part 2 of 4, 1985-1986 (Box-folder 4/14)
  - Analytic Self-evaluation Report Exhibits -- Part 3 of 4, 1985-1986 (Box-folder 4/15)
  - Analytic Self-evaluation Report Exhibits -- Part 4 of 4, 1985-1986 (Box-folder 4/16)
  - Final program year 1980 Strategic planning report (Box-folder 4/17)
  - Self Evaluation Report for Accreditation by National Association of Trade and Technical Schools, 1977 (Box-folder 6/34)
  - Self Evaluation Report for Accreditation by National Association of Trade and Technical Schools including Document M -- Part 1 of 2, 1977 (Box-folder 6/35)
  - Self Evaluation Report for Accreditation by National Association of Trade and Technical Schools including Document M -- Part 2 of 2, 1977 (Box-folder 6/36)
  - Council of Non Collegiate Continuing Education Site Visit, 1986 (Box-folder 6/37)
- CONTRACTS, 1968-1983; SERIES 6 (Box-folder 5/5 - 6/33)
  - King-Snohomish Manpower Consortium contract modification no. 1, 1977 (Box-folder 5/5)
  - SOIC Application for CMP (Comprehensive Manpower Program) contract, 1973 (Box-folder 5/6)
  - Application to King-Snohomish Manpower Consortium, 1975 (Box-folder 5/7)
  - Application to King-Snohomish Manpower Consortium -- Part 1 of 2, 1976 (Box-folder 5/8)
  - Application to King-Snohomish Manpower Consortium -- Part 2 of 2, 1976 (Box-folder 5/9)
  - Washington State Employment Security Dept. contract for Alternatives for Women Project, 1977 (Box-folder 5/10)
  - Apprenticeship Outreach Program contract, 1979 (Box-folder 5/11)
  - King-Snohomish Manpower Consortium CETA Title IIB contract, 1979 (Box-folder 5/12)
  - Modification of Agreement with Washington State Commission for Vocational Education for Projection Non-Tradition, 1978-1979 (Box-folder 5/13)
  - Heat loss calculations contract with Seattle City Light, 1977 (Box-folder 5/14)
  - King-Snohomish Manpower Consortium contract, 1978 (Box-folder 5/15)
  - Contract with State for Adult Basic Education, 1977-1978 (Box-folder 5/16)
  - King-Snohomish Manpower Consortium contract, 1978 (Box-folder 5/17)
  - YCCIP (Youth Community Conservation and Improvement Projects) contract, 1979 (Box-folder 5/18)
  - YCCIP Youth Community Repair Project contract, 1979 (Box-folder 5/19)
  - YIEPP (Youth Incentive Entitlement Pilot Projects) Enrichment contract, 1979 (Box-folder 5/20)
  - ES/PSE (Employment Security/Public Service Employment) contract CETA Title VI A, 1979 (Box-folder 5/21)
  - City PSE (Public Service Employment) contract, 1979 (Box-folder 5/22)
  - State ES/PSE (Employment Security/Public Service Employment) contract, 1979 (Box-folder 5/23)
  - State ES/PSE (Employment Security/Public Service Employment) contract Title VI Food Industry Project, 1979 (Box-folder 5/24)
  - Solar Related Vocational Training Curriculum, 1979 (Box-folder 5/25)
  - King-Snohomish Manpower Consortium contract -- part 1 of 2, 1977 (Box-folder 5/26)
  - King-Snohomish Manpower Consortium contract -- part 2 of 2, 1977 (Box-folder 5/27)
  - YCCIP (Youth Community Conservation and Improvement Projects) Weatherization Modification, 1979 (Box-folder 5/28)
  - First SOIC proposal, 1968 (Box-folder 5/29)
  - First SOIC proposal correspondence, 1968 (Box-folder 5/30)
  - King-Snohomish Manpower Consortium contract modification 2, 1977 (Box-folder 5/31)
  - Application for King-Snohomish Manpower Consortium contract, 1974 (Box-folder 5/32)
  - Betty Emry contract, 1979 (Box-folder 5/33)
  - Head Start food service contract, 1976 (Box-folder 5/34)
  - CIP/SPS (Career Intern Program/Seattle Public Schools) contract, 1978-1979 (Box-folder 5/35)
  - Consumers' Education contract, 1976 (Box-folder 5/36)
  - DSHS (Department of Social and Health Services) contract, 1977 (Box-folder 5/37)
  - DCD (Department of Community Development) Emergency/Minor Home Repair Program contract, 1978 (Box-folder 5/38)
  - Vocational Education Services Program CETA Individual Referral contracts, 1977 (Box-folder 5/39)
  - Indochinese Resettlement Project contract, 1976 (Box-folder 5/40)
  - Solar Related Vocational Training, 1978 (Box-folder 5/41)
  - King-Snohomish Manpower Consortium Title - I contract, 1977 (Box-folder 5/42)
  - Maritime Foss Launch and Tug contract, 1979 (Box-folder 5/43)
  - Superintendent of Public Instruction-Indochinese Project contract, 1979 (Box-folder 6/1)
  - Lockheed Modification Agreement, 1979 (Box-folder 6/2)
  - State Board of Community College Education contract, 1976 (Box-folder 6/3)
  - Service Bureau Company contract, 1978 (Box-folder 6/4)
  - KSMC STIP (Skills Training Improvement Program) contract, 1978 (Box-folder 6/5)
  - Dept. of Transportation Supportive Services -- Highway Construction Training Program contract, 1978 (Box-folder 6/6)
  - Employment Security Dept. Work Incentive Program contract, 1976 (Box-folder 6/7)
  - CAMP contract -- Senior Lunch Program, 1977 (Box-folder 6/8)
  - Alternatives for Women contract, 1977-1978 (Box-folder 6/9)
  - Washington State Commission for Vocational Education CCOE contract, 1976 (Box-folder 6/10)
  - CETA (Comprehensive Employment and Training Act) PSE (Public Service Employment) contract, 1976 (Box-folder 6/11)
  - City of Seattle Dept. of Community Development contract, 1976 (Box-folder 6/12)
  - CIP (Career Intern Program)/Seattle Public Schools contract, 1978 (Box-folder 6/13)
  - Commission of Vocational Education contract, 1976 (Box-folder 6/14)
  - Employment Security Job Development Subcontract, 1975-1976 (Box-folder 6/15)
  - Professional Technical and Services contract, 1978 (Box-folder 6/16)
  - Fred Walsh contract for Technical Assistance and Graphic Design and Coordination (Box-folder 6/17)
  - Employment Security Department Public Service Employment contract, 1977 (Box-folder 6/18)
  - Lockheed Welder Training contract, 1975-1977 (Box-folder 6/19)
  - Photographic Services contract, 1974 (Box-folder 6/20)
  - Seattle Public Schools Work Training Program contract, 1974-1976 (Box-folder 6/21)
  - Lockheed Shipbuilding and Todd Shipyard Construction contract, 1978-1979 (Box-folder 6/22)
  - Pre-Vocational and Technical Training Project Proposal May 1966 (Box-folder 6/23)
  - Pre-Vocational and Technical Training Project Proposal August 1966 (Box-folder 6/24)
  - Economic Development Administration Development Facilities Grant proposal -- part 1 of 2, 1971 (Box-folder 6/25)
  - Economic Development Administration Development Facilities Grant proposal -- part 2 of 2, 1971 (Box-folder 6/26)
  - Occupational Skills Training proposal, 1983 (Box-folder 6/27)
  - Occupational Skills Training proposal -- Curriculum Attachment, 1983 (Box-folder 6/28)
  - Economic Development Administration Building project, 1972 (Box-folder 6/29)
  - Certificate of Accreditation from National Association of Trade and Technical Schools, 1978 (Box-folder 6/30)
  - Economic Development Administration Building Expansion -- part 1 of 2, 1979 (Box-folder 6/31)
  - Economic Development Administration Building Expansion -- part 2 of 2, 1979 (Box-folder 6/32)
  - Parking Deck proposal, 1983 (Box-folder 6/33)
- PUBLICITY AND PUBLIC RELATIONS RECORDS, 1967-1985; SERIES 7
  - Speeches, Advertising and Publications, 1967-1985; Subseries 1 (Box-folder 6/38 - 6/48, 7/7, 7/28, 7/40, 11/14)
    - Seattle Opportunities Industrialization Center testimony to House Subcommittee on Census and Population, 1980 (Box-folder 6/38)
    - Funding diversification speech, 1980 (Box-folder 6/39)
    - Staff orientation speech, 1980 (Box-folder 6/40)
    - Private Industry Council remarks, 1981 (Box-folder 6/41)
    - Girls Club of Puget Sound speech, 1981 (Box-folder 6/42)
    - Testimony before Joint Education and Higher Education Committee, 1982 (Box-folder 6/43)
    - Role of OICs in 1980s, 1982 (Box-folder 6/44)
    - Garth Mangum remarks to Adherent Forum, 1981 (Box-folder 6/45)
    - Testimony before National Commission for Manpower Policy, 1977 (Box-folder 6/46)
    - Newspaper ads, 1985-1986 (Box-folder 6/47)
    - Newspaper ads, 1984-1985 (Box-folder 6/48)
    - Newspaper and television ads, 1983-1984 (Box-folder 6/49)
    - OIC Publications and Press Coverage, 1974-1976 (Box-folder 7/7)
    - Seattle Opportunities Industrialization Center Annual Report, 1973 (Box-folder 7/28)
    - Information brochures and articles, 1966-1967 (Box-folder 7/40)
    - Seattle Opportunities Industrialization Center song recording, undated (Box-folder 9/4)
    - Building presentation recording, undated (Box-folder 11/14)
  - Photographs, 1967-1985; Subseries 2 (Box-folder 7/23 - 7/27, 7/29 - 7/39, 8/12, 9/1 - 9/3, 9/5 - 9/40, 10/1 - 10/19, 11/1 - 11/13)
    - Visiting dignitaries (including Julian Bond, Whitney Young, John Lindsay, Moon Landrieu), 1967-1971 (Box-folder 7/23)
    - OICs of America Region IX Conference Program, 1967 (Box-folder 7/24)
    - J.L. Williams, 1967, undated (Box-folder 7/25)
    - Governor's Signing SOIC Week, undated (Box-folder 7/26)
    - Fund Drive Press Conference, 1970 (Box-folder 7/27)
    - Day Camp Open House, 1968 (Box-folder 7/29)
    - Basketball Game, 1968 (Box-folder 7/30)
    - Photograph -- King County Fair, undated (Box-folder 7/31)
    - Christmas Parties, 1967?-1971 (Box-folder 7/32)
    - Community Picnic -- "Family Affair", 1973 (Box-folder 7/33)
    - Dedication, 1967 (Box-folder 7/34)
    - Photographs -- Miscellaneous -- Part 1 of 3, undated, 1967-1973 (Box-folder 7/35)
    - Photographs -- Miscellaneous -- Part 2 of 3, undated, 1967-1973 (Box-folder 7/36)
    - Photographs -- Miscellaneous -- Part 3 of 3, undated, 1967-1973 (Box-folder 7/37)
    - Playthell Benjamin -- Photographs (including Robert F. Kennedy), Letters and Clippings, 1966-1972 (Box-folder 7/38)
    - Graduation, undated (Box-folder 7/39)
    - Photographs and Publicity -- Teleauction, 1971-1972 (Box-folder 8/12)
    - Family Church Sunday, 1972 (Box-folder 9/1)
    - Trainees, undated, 1967-1968 (Box-folder 9/2)
    - Mayors' Conference, 1971 (Box-folder 9/3)
    - departure to San Jose Regional Meeting, 1970 (Box-folder 9/5)
    - Recruiting, 1967 (Box-folder 9/6)
    - Public Defender and Trainee Council Meeting, 1970 (Box-folder 9/7)
    - Speakers' Bureau Party, 1971 (Box-folder 9/8)
    - Presbytery Check, 1968 (Box-folder 9/9)
    - Picnic, 1968-1970 (Box-folder 9/10)
    - Open House, 1971 (Box-folder 9/11)
    - Graduation at Seattle U, 1969 (Box-folder 9/12)
    - Insurance Class, 1970 (Box-folder 9/13)
    - Success Stories Annual Report -- Insight, 1973 (Box-folder 9/14)
    - Rev. McKinney, undated (Box-folder 9/15)
    - Linda Austin, 1980 (Box-folder 9/16)
    - 17th Annual Convocation (Phoenix AZ), 1981 (Box-folder 9/17)
    - SOIC Building, 1982 (Box-folder 9/18)
    - Rev. Leon Sullivan, undated (Box-folder 9/19)
    - Plaques, undated (Box-folder 9/20)
    - Community Picnic, undated (Box-folder 9/21)
    - Biennial Report, undated (Box-folder 9/22)
    - unidentified occasion, 1978 (Box-folder 9/23)
    - Jim Williams, undated (Box-folder 9/24)
    - Appreciation Dinner, undated (Box-folder 9/25)
    - Slick Watts, undated (Box-folder 9/26)
    - Pacific Coast Investment Company, undated (Box-folder 9/27)
    - Old Skill Center, 1967-1968 (Box-folder 9/28)
    - Rogers Morton (Secretary, U. S. Dept. of Commerce), 1975 (Box-folder 9/29)
    - Jim Williams's 5th Anniversary, 1975 (Box-folder 9/30)
    - NATTS (National Association of Trade and Technical Schools) Accreditation Ceremony, 1979 (Box-folder 9/31)
    - Trainees at work -- Part 1 of 5, undated (Box-folder 9/32)
    - Trainees at work -- Part 2 of 5, undated (Box-folder 9/33)
    - Trainees at work -- Part 3 of 5, undated (Box-folder 9/34)
    - Trainees at work -- Part 4 of 5, undated (Box-folder 9/35)
    - Trainees at work -- Part 5 of 5, undated (Box-folder 9/36)
    - Unidentified Occasions, undated (Box-folder 9/37)
    - Accreditation Ceremonies, 1979 (Box-folder 9/38)
    - Unidentified Event, 1980 (Box-folder 9/39)
    - Miscellaneous contact sheets & negatives, undated (Box-folder 9/40)
    - Welding, undated (Box-folder 10/1)
    - Biennial Report Photographs, c. 1975 (Box-folder 10/2)
    - Movie film, undated (Box-folder 10/3)
    - SOIC Video Reel, 1982 (Box-folder 10/4)
    - SOIC Videocassette of KCTS Doc:"In the Best of Times", 1981 (Box-folder 10/5)
    - Photographs -- part 1 of 3, undated (Box-folder 10/6)
    - Photographs -- part 2 of 3, undated (Box-folder 10/7)
    - Photographs -- part 3 of 3, undated (Box-folder 10/8)
    - Mayor Charles T. Royer, undated (Box-folder 10/9)
    - Graduations, undated, 1968-1985 (Box-folder 10/10)
    - Media Luncheon, undated (Box-folder 10/11)
    - Unidentified Event, undated (Box-folder 10/12)
    - Rex D. Jones Farewell, undated (Box-folder 10/13)
    - Photographs, undated, 1967-1968 (Box-folder 10/14)
    - Souvenir Book Photographs, undated (Box-folder 10/15)
    - Brotherhood Day Observance, 1973 (Box-folder 10/16)
    - Photographs, undated (Box-folder 10/17)
    - Photographs, undated (Box-folder 10/18)
    - SOIC Public Service Announcement Videocassette -- KIRO, 1977 (Box-folder 10/19)
    - SOIC Building Dedication Videotape -- Part 1 of 2, 1974 (Box-folder 11/1)
    - SOIC Building Dedication Videotape -- Part 2 of 2, 1974 (Box-folder 11/2)
    - Photographs, undated (Box-folder 11/3)
    - Photographs, undated, 1978-1982 (Box-folder 11/4)
    - Photographs, undated (Box-folder 11/5)
    - Photographs, undated, 1978-1980 (Box-folder 11/6)
    - Photo negatives (part 1 of 4), undated (Box-folder 11/7)
    - Photo negatives (part 2 of 4), undated (Box-folder 11/8)